Guide to the Ralph Hodgson Papers
Yale University Library
Bagnold, Enid.; Baker, Silvia.; Blunden, Edmund, 1896-1974.; Bryher, 1894-; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965.; Eliot, Vivienne, 1888-1947.; Hodgson, Aurelia Bolliger.; Hodgson, Ralph, 1871-1962.; Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1909-1975.; Richards, I. A. (Ivor Armstrong), 1893-1979.; Russell, George William, 1867-1935.; Sassoon, Siegfried, 1886-1967.; Smith, Dorothy Hall.; Whitney, W. Bevan.; American poetry --20th century.; Authors, American --20th century.; Authors, Japanese --20th century.; Bull terrier.; English poetry --20th century.; Poets, American --20th century.; Poets, English --20th century.; Poets, English --20th century --Archives.; World War, 1914-1918 --Personal narratives, British.; Cartoons (humorous images); Maps; Photographs.; Sketchbooks.; Sketches.
Authors
Hodgson, Ralph, 1871-1962.; Sassoon, Siegfried, 1886-1967.
Occupations and Functions
Poets, English.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1887-1976; Series I.; 16.2' (40 boxes)
  Series I, Correspondence, is organized into eight subseries: Personal Correspondence, Third Party Correspondence, Permissions, Publishers Inquiries, Orders, Other Requests and Invitations, Fan Mail, and Related Material. Orders and Fan Mail are arranged chronologically; the other subseries are arranged alphabetically. Letters from correspondents not listed individually may be found in "letter" general files.
  - PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" general, 1924-73, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Abbott, Charles D., 1955, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Abbott, Claude Colleer, 1920-62 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adams, James Truslow, 1933 Oct 30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Adelman, Seymour, 1939-73, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Incorporated, 1955 Nov 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Allentuck, Marcia, 1970-71, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Amy, Ernest F., 1955, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Anglo-French Poetry Society
      See: Sitwell, Edith, Box 25 folder 505
    - Arkenburgh, Miriam Vedder, 1961-74, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
    - "B" general, 1916-62, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - Bacon, Leonard and Martha, 1946-49 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
    - Bacon, Leonard and Martha, 1950-62, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 21-24)
    - Bagnold, Enid, [1916]-73, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25-27)
    - Baker, Silvia
      - Correspondence, 1924-29 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
      - Correspondence, 1930-34 (Box 2, Folder 30-32)
      - Correspondence, 1935-39 (Box 2, Folder 33-35)
      - Correspondence, [1940-48] (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Correspondence, 1950-54 (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
      - Correspondence, 1955-59 (Box 3, Folder 39-43)
      - Correspondence, 1960-67, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 44-46)
    - Beam, Mary, [1960-65] (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Bechtel, Louise, [1941]-70, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 48-52)
    - Beeby, Edward, 1951-52 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
      See: Yale University Library, Box 30 folder 614
    - Benét, William Rose, 1916-50 (Box 3, Folder 54-55)
    - Benson, Theodora, 1932 Jul 14 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Beresford, J. D., 1930 Nov 14 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Berryman, John, 1971-72 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Bertram Rota Ltd. Booksellers, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Besier, Rudolf, 1913-39, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 60-61)
    - Betjeman, John, 1971, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Biggins, Joe, 1944-71 (Box 4, Folder 63-64)
    - Binyon, Cicely, 1929, 1931, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Blakeney, E. H., [1917-34] (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Blanchard, Vivian and Lucy, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Blunden, Edmund, 1920-35, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 68-73)
    - Boggs, Barbara, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Bonham-Carter, Violet, 1932 Jun (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Brewster, Esther, 1959-64, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 76-77)
    - Bridges, Robert, 1923-24, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - British Consulate General, Chicago, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - British Consulate General, Mukden, [1934 Dec 21] (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - British Consulate, Tokyo, n.y. Oct 26 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Brown, Ivor, 1971 Dec 14 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Brown, Richard, [1933]-37, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Bryher, 1953-71, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 84-89)
      See also: Pearson, Norman Holmes, Box 19 folder 390
    - Bush, Lewis W., 1938, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1941-63 (Box 5, Folder 91-94)
    - "C" general, 1930-71, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 95-96)
    - Campbell, John S., 1956, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Campbell, R. R., 1933, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Cane, Melville, 1961 Dec 11 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Cartwright, H. Arthur, 1960-61, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Chalmers, Gordon and Roberta, [1941-62], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 101-103)
    - Charles Sessler, Bookseller and Printseller
      See: Sessler's Book Shop, Box 25 folder 497
    - Chase, Lewis and Emma, 1930-66, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 104-108)
    - Churchill, Lady Randolph Spencer, 1932, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Clark, Leonard, 1971 Dec 14 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Clemens, Cyril, 1936-62 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Clerk, Stuart, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Clodd, H. Alan, 1961-73 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Colefax, Sibyl, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Colquhoun, David and Shirley, 1949-71, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 115-120)
    - Coltman, Ella, 1931-32 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Consulate of Japan, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Cosgrove, L. D., 1929-32 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Cournos, John, 19[15]-47 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Craig, Edward Gordon
      See: Godwin, Edward, Box 11 folder 213
    - Custance, Olive
      See: Douglas, Olive, Box 8 folder 150
    - "D" general, 1921-62 (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - Dalmon, Charles, [1932]-33 (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Dargan, Olive, 1959-60 (Box 7, Folder 127)
    - Dartmouth College Library, 1939-46 (Box 7, Folder 128)
    - Davies, W. H., 1920-32, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - Davis, Elmer, 1955 Jul 4 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Davis, Helen Bayley, [1939-53] (Box 7, Folder 131-132)
    - Davis, Mary, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - Davison, Edward, 1938-59 (Box 7, Folder 134-138)
    - Delaforce, Wog, 1919-54 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - De la Mare, Walter and Richard, [1915?]-70, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 140-141)
    - del Re, Arundel, 1935-54, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - Denson, Alan, 19[50]-60 (Box 7, Folder 143-144)
    - Dewar, G. A. B., 1919-22 (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - Doi, Kochi, 1927-72 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - Donnelly, Ian, 1953-56 (Box 7, Folder 147-148)
    - [Dorling], -----, [1916]-18 (Box 7, Folder 148a)
      Letters are signed "Old Dor"
    - Dorn, Marion V., [1932]-33 (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Douglas, Olive, [1917-18], n.d. (Box 8, Folder 150)
    - Drinkwater, John, 1918-33 (Box 8, Folder 151)
    - Druces Attlee, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 152)
    - Duffy, Charles, 1948-71, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 153-156)
    - Dwork, Kermit, 1948-62, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 157-158)
    - "E" general, 1921, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - Eben Demarest Trust, 1959-62 (Box 8, Folder 160)
    - Eckler, Eric and Mary, [1946]-71, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 161-166)
    - Eliot, T. S., 1932-63 (Box 9, Folder 167-168)
    - Eliot, Valerie, 1965-74, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 169-171)
      See also: Oversize, box 64, folder 1132
    - Eliot, Vivienne, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 172-175)
    - Empson, William, [1933-35], n.d. (Box 9, Folder 176-177)
    - Erlebach, Donald E., 1961-62 (Box 9, Folder 178)
    - Eugene Field Society, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - "F" general, 1919-42 (Box 9, Folder 180)
    - Faber Faber Ltd., 1939-48, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 181)
    - Fagan, Elizabeth and Monica, 1918-48, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 182)
    - Farano, Michel, 1952-61 (Box 9, Folder 183-184)
    - Fenton, Colin, [1960]-72 (Box 9, Folder 185-188)
    - Fenton, Colin, 1973-75 (Box 10, Folder 189-191)
    - Findley, Allan G. and Michael, 1960-71 (Box 10, Folder 192-193)
    - Fisher, Jerry, 1959-60 (Box 10, Folder 194)
    - Fisk, Earl, 1946-[48] (Box 10, Folder 195)
    - Fountain, Paul, 1917 May 25 (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - Fraser, Claud Lovat, 1915 (Box 10, Folder 196a)
    - Fraser, Dallas, 1932-35 (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - Fry, C. B., 1946-47 (Box 10, Folder 198-200)
    - Frye, Burton, 1961 Feb 16 (Box 10, Folder 201)
    - Fujii, Haruhiko, 1971-72 (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - Fulton, A. S., 1948-73 (Box 10, Folder 203-205)
      See also: Oversize, box 65, folder 1140
    - Furman, Dorothy, 1915 Apr 7 (Box 10, Folder 206)
    - Furse, Celia, 1931-39, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 207)
    - "G" general, [1915]-70 (Box 10, Folder 208)
    - Galsworthy, John, 1917-18 (Box 10, Folder 209)
    - Gawsworth, John, 1961 Jan (Box 10, Folder 210)
    - George Allen Unwin Ltd., 1926-47 (Box 10, Folder 211)
    - Gertler, Mark, 1929-35 (Box 11, Folder 212)
    - Godwin, Edward, 1920 Dec 14 (Box 11, Folder 213)
    - Goldman, Peretz, [1947-59] (Box 11, Folder 214-218)
    - Goodale, Ralph, 1946-[48] (Box 11, Folder 219)
    - Grant, Duncan, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 220)
    - Grant, Ethel and Mary, 1940-[48] (Box 11, Folder 221)
    - Great Britain. Home Office, 1938 Oct 5 (Box 11, Folder 222)
    - Griffin, Velma, 1960-65, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 223-224)
    - Griggs, Frederick Landseer Maur, 1919-21 (Box 11, Folder 225)
    - "H" general, 1919-72 (Box 11, Folder 226-228)
    - Haddons, Chemist, Optician, Stationer and Wine Merchant, 1940-53 (Box 11, Folder 229)
    - Hall, Donald, n.y. Jan 22 (Box 11, Folder 230)
    - Hall, Dorothy
      See: Smith, Dorothy Hall, Box 25 folder 506
    - Hall, Sam, [1946]-71, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 231-232)
    - Hani, Keiko and Motoko, 1931 Jul 7 (Box 11a, Folder 232a)
    - Hani, Keiko and Motoko, 1931-63, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 233-234)
    - Hansen, Harry, 1941-[48] (Box 12, Folder 235)
    - Harding, Ridge, 1924, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 236)
    - Hardy, Thomas, 1919 Oct 23 (Box 12, Folder 237)
    - Hartley, Peggy
      See: Nunn, Peggy, Box 18 folder 369
    - Harvard University Library, [1949 Mar 12] (Box 12, Folder 238)
    - Hassall, Christopher, 1954-55 (Box 12, Folder 239)
      See also: Box 24, folder 489
    - Hauptman, Phillis, 1919-30, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 240)
    - Hay, Silvia
      See: Baker, Silvia, Box 2 folder 28
    - Hayward, F. H., 1921-28 (Box 12, Folder 241)
    - Heath, Cecil, 1939-56 (Box 12, Folder 242-243)
    - Henson, Violet, ca. 1919-63, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 244)
    - Hillyer, Robert, [1948]-52 (Box 12, Folder 245-246)
    - Hobbs, Valine, [1940-47], n.d. (Box 12, Folder 247)
    - Hodgson, Aurelia, 1955 Aug 10 (Box 12, Folder 248)
    - Hodgson, Enid and Robert, [1962]-71 (Box 12, Folder 249)
    - Hollender, V. C., [1938]-61 (Box 12, Folder 250)
    - Holmes, John, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 251)
    - Hunter, Edith, Eileen, and Beryl, 1932-38 (Box 12, Folder 252-253)
    - Hutchinson, George, 1937-[38] (Box 12, Folder 254)
    - Hutchinson, Sherry, 1940-71 (Box 12, Folder 255-258)
    - Huxley, Julian, 1931-[32], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 259)
    - "I" general, 1927, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 260)
    - Ingpen, Rosalind, 1928-[33] (Box 13, Folder 261)
    - Izant, Grace and Robert, 1953-71 (Box 13, Folder 262-263)
    - "J" general, 1932-43 (Box 13, Folder 264)
    - Jackson, Holbrook, 1931-50, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 265-267)
    - John Grant Booksellers Limited, 1940-57, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 268)
    - "K" general, 1932-72 (Box 13, Folder 269)
    - Kauffer, E. McKnight, 1932-34 (Box 13, Folder 270)
    - Kelly, Fred, [1957]-58 (Box 13, Folder 271-272)
    - Kelsey, W. K., 1955-[61], n.d. (Box 13, Folder 273-274)
    - Ketcham, Charles and Lucile, [1946]-71, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 275-278)
    - Kinner, Joan, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 279)
    - Kirkup, James, 1971-72 (Box 14, Folder 280)
    - Kobayashi, Atsuo
      See: Sweetser, Wesley D., Box 27 folder 549
    - Koteliansky, Samuel, 1930-55 (Box 14, Folder 281-283)
    - Krise, Nelle, 1946-75, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 284-288)
    - "L" general, 1928-72 (Box 14, Folder 289)
    - Lape, James T., 1946-61 (Box 14, Folder 290)
    - Laport, Vivian, 1965-66 (Box 14, Folder 291)
    - Leach, Henry, 1941-42 (Box 14, Folder 292-294)
    - Lewis, Robert, 1949-52 (Box 14, Folder 295-296)
    - Litvinoff, Ivy, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 297)
    - Lloyd, Bertram, 1917-39, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 298-300)
    - Long, Haniel, [1942-46], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 301)
    - Loucks, Ethel
      See: Grant, Ethel, Box 11 folder 221
    - Loveland, Roelif, 1946-54 (Box 15, Folder 302)
    - Low, Lettice, 1917-22, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 303)
    - Lowith, Ada, 1938-39, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 304)
    - Lynd, Sylvia, 1932 Mar 23 (Box 15, Folder 305)
    - "M" general, 1923-52, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 306)
    - Maas, William and Winifred, 1945-63 (Box 15, Folder 307-316)
    - McCord, David, 1942-45 (Box 15, Folder 317-318)
    - McKenna, Pamela, [1931]-32, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 319-321)
    - MacMillan Co, Ltd., 1927-72, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 322-325)
    - Marsh, Edward, 1915-45 (Box 16, Folder 326)
    - Martha Kinney Cooper Ohioana Library Association, 1961-68 (Box 16, Folder 327)
    - Martin, Houston, 1933-46 (Box 16, Folder 328)
    - Masefield, John, 1954-[64] (Box 16, Folder 329-331)
    - Mayfield, John, 1955-64 (Box 16, Folder 332-336)
    - Mayfield, John, 1965-74 (Box 17, Folder 337-338)
    - Meynell, Everard, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 339)
    - Meynell, Francis, 1922-[31] (Box 17, Folder 340)
    - Milne, Herbert John Mansfield, 1952-53, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 341)
    - Mirams, Doris, 1954-60 (Box 17, Folder 342)
    - Moncrieff, George Scott, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 343)
    - Monro, Alida, 1914-57 (Box 17, Folder 344-345)
    - Moore, Evelyn Stuart, 1919-20, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 346)
    - Moore, John Travers, 1943-55, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 347)
    - Morgan, Charles, 1932, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 348)
    - Morley, Christopher, 1946 May-Jun (Box 17, Folder 348a)
      See also: Box 41, folder 876a
    - Morley, F. V., 1932-55, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 349-354)
    - Morrell, Ottoline, [1931]-34 (Box 17, Folder 355-356)
    - Morrison, Ian, [1936?-38] (Box 18, Folder 357)
    - Murdoch, Royal, 1926-72 (Box 18, Folder 358-360)
    - "N" general, 19[28]-71 (Box 18, Folder 361)
    - Nash, Paul, 1920 Mar 17 (Box 18, Folder 362)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters (U.S.), 1946-52 (Box 18, Folder 363)
    - Newland, Paul D., 1949 (Box 18, Folder 364)
    - Newson, Ranald, [1946] Nov 26 (Box 18, Folder 365)
    - Nichols, Robert, 1924-32 (Box 18, Folder 366)
    - Norman, Herbert, 1931-38 (Box 18, Folder 367)
    - North, Sterling, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 368)
    - Nunn, Peggy, [1932-55], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 369-376)
    - "O" general, 1932-71 (Box 19, Folder 377)
    - Oakes, Tom, 1961, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 378)
    - Oakley, Ruth, [1957-63], n.d. (Box 19, Folder 379-383)
    - Ogden, C. K., [1932 Feb 1] (Box 19, Folder 384)
    - Empty folder (Box 19, Folder 385)
    - "Old Dor"
      See: Dorling, ----, Box 7 folder 148a
    - Olivier, Edith, [1932-33], n.d. (Box 19, Folder 386)
    - Osborne, E. A., 1932-33 (Box 19, Folder 387)
    - "P" general, 1928-53 (Box 19, Folder 388)
    - Palmer, Herbert E., 1920 Mar 12 (Box 19, Folder 389)
    - Pancoast, Sherry
      See: Hutchinson, Sherry, Box 12 folder 255
    - Paul, Laura
      See: Rankin, Laura, Box 20 folder 415
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes
      - Correspondence, 1942-59 (Box 19, Folder 390-393)
        Includes postcards with postscripts from Bryher, dated Nov 10 1954 and Aug 4 1958
      - Correspondence, 1960-64 (Box 19, Folder 394-398)
        Includes postcards with postscripts from Bryher, dated [Jun] 28 1961, Jan 28 1962 and Aug 19 1962
      - Correspondence, 1965-69 (Box 20, Folder 399-401)
        Folder 401 includes Kochi Doi, "Ralph Hodgson," typescript photocopy
      - Correspondence, 1970-74 (Box 20, Folder 402-406)
        Folder 405 includes Eigo Bungako Sekai vol. 6, no. 6. Ralph Hodgson issue. Translated by Takahiro Kamogawa. Typescript, corrected
      - Correspondence, 1975, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 407-408)
    - Peebles, Mary, [1961]-62 (Box 20, Folder 409)
    - Phillips, William J., 1939-54, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 410)
    - Quennell, Peter, [1930] (Box 20, Folder 411)
    - "R" general, 1930-72 (Box 20, Folder 412)
    - Ramsbottom, E. W., 1919 (Box 20, Folder 413)
    - Raney, M. Llewellyn, 1938-42 (Box 20, Folder 414)
    - Rankin, Laura, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 415-416)
    - Rankin, Laura, 1947-63, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 417-421)
    - Richards, I. A. and Dorothea, 1932-[73], n.d. (Box 21, Folder 422-426)
    - Richards, Robert and Chris, 1940-56 (Box 21, Folder 427-430)
      See also: Oversize, box 65, folder 1141
    - Richards, Robert and Chris, 1959-71, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 431-433)
    - Robbins, S. Martha, [1946?-62] (Box 22, Folder 434)
    - Roberts, R. Ellis and Harriet (Box 22, Folder 435)
    - Robertson, David, 1939-69, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 436-445)
    - Rothenstein, Albert, Elizabeth, Rachel, and William, 1921-42, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 446-447)
    - Royde-Smith, Naomi G., 1920-33, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 448)
    - "S" general, 1917-64 (Box 23, Folder 449-450)
    - St. Martin's Press Incorporated, 1960-65 (Box 23, Folder 451)
    - Saito, Takeshi, 1970-72 (Box 23, Folder 452)
    - Salt, Henry, 1926-55, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 453-461)
    - Samuel, Herbert, 1932, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 462)
    - Sanders, Gerald, 1935-55 (Box 23, Folder 463-464)
    - Sansom, Katharine, 1933 Jan 10 (Box 23, Folder 465)
    - Sarton, May, [1942] Mar 4 (Box 23, Folder 466)
    - Sassoon, Siegfried
      - Correspondence, 1923-29 (Box 24, Folder 467-469)
      - Correspondence, 1930-35 (Box 24, Folder 470-475)
      - Correspondence, 1936-40 (Box 24, Folder 476-479)
      - Correspondence, 1941-45 (Box 24, Folder 480-483)
      - Correspondence, 1946-50 (Box 24, Folder 484-486)
      - Correspondence, 1951-55 (Box 24, Folder 487-489)
        Contains letter by Christopher Hassall dated 1954 Apr 8, forwarded by Sassoon to Hodgson
      - Correspondence, 1957, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 490)
      - Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 491)
      - Typed transcripts of correspondence from 1923-1934 (Box 25, Folder 492-493)
    - Saturday Review of Literature, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 494)
      See also: Benét, William Rose, Box 3 folder 54
    - Saul, George Brandon, 1943-71 (Box 25, Folder 495)
    - Schroeder, Ralph L., [1961]-63 (Box 25, Folder 496)
    - Sessler's Book Shop, 1942-[61], n.d. (Box 25, Folder 497)
    - Shechtman, Joseph, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 498)
    - Sinkinson, Walter, 1946-75, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 499-503)
    - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1942-59 (Box 25, Folder 504)
    - Sitwell, Edith, 1921-61, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 505)
    - Smith, Dorothy Hall
      - Correspondence, 1940-44 (Box 25, Folder 506-508)
      - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 509-513)
      - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 514-516)
      - Correspondence, 1947-50 (Box 26, Folder 517-520)
      - Correspondence, 1951-54 (Box 26, Folder 521-523)
        Folder 523 includes "Silver Wedding and Other Poems" pamphlet
      - Correspondence, 1955-65, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 524-528)
        Folder 525 includes "Songs to Our Surnames" pamphlet
    - Smith, LeRoy, [1945]-52 (Box 27, Folder 529-531)
    - Sparrow, John, 1953-71 (Box 27, Folder 532-533)
    - Spencer, Gilbert and Ursula, [1931-35], n.d. (Box 27, Folder 534)
    - Spender, Stephen, 1959-60 (Box 27, Folder 535)
    - Spicer-Simson, Theodore, 1922-54, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 536-538)
    - Stead, William Force, n.y. May 31 (Box 27, Folder 539)
    - Stephens, James, 1911-28 (Box 27, Folder 540)
    - Stires, David, 1958-[61] (Box 27, Folder 541-542)
    - Stone, Reynolds, 1959 Jan 10 (Box 27, Folder 543)
    - Strong, R. A. G., 1922-32 (Box 27, Folder 544)
    - Sweeney, John L., 1942-[62], n.d. (Box 27, Folder 545-548)
    - Sweetser, Wesley D., 1959-74 (Box 27, Folder 549-552)
      Contains photographs of Hodgson's letters to Atsuo Kobayashi
    - Swift, F. H., 1958-59 (Box 28, Folder 553)
    - "T" general, 1941-63 (Box 28, Folder 554)
    - T. D. Webster, 1951-52, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 555)
    - Taketomo, Torao and Yoshi, 1933-71, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 556)
    - Taylor, Walter, 1931-32 (Box 28, Folder 557)
    - Thayer, Frederick A., 1946-[51], n.d. (Box 28, Folder 558-559)
    - Thomas, Edward, 1914 Nov 19 (Box 28, Folder 560)
    - Thornburg, S. Raymond, 1934-38 (Box 28, Folder 561)
    - Thorp, Joseph, 1928, 1930 (Box 28, Folder 562)
    - Tibbs, Doris, 1929-[54] (Box 28, Folder 563-565)
    - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1947-54 (Box 28, Folder 566-567)
    - Torrence, Ridgely, [1946 May 3] (Box 28, Folder 568)
    - Turner, Walter and Delphine, 1920-[38], n.d. (Box 28, Folder 569-570)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 571)
    - Untermeyer, Louis and Esther, 1930-46 (Box 28, Folder 572-573)
    - Van Pelt, Daniel J., 1955-61 (Box 28, Folder 574)
    - Verner, Edward, 1918-[19] (Box 28, Folder 575)
    - Vodrey, Jackman S., [1960-62], n.d. (Box 29, Folder 576)
    - Vodrey, William H., Jr. and Joseph Kelly, 1960-61 (Box 29, Folder 577)
    - "W" general, 1918-71 (Box 29, Folder 578)
    - Walston, Charles, 1922-23 (Box 29, Folder 579)
    - Waterlow, Sydney, 1931 Sep 19 (Box 29, Folder 580)
    - Webbe, Ernest A., 1946-47 (Box 29, Folder 581)
    - Wells, Marjorie, 1938-59, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 582-586)
    - Weygandt, Cornelius, 1927-[57], n.d. (Box 29, Folder 587-589)
    - Wheatcroft, Christabel, 1946-62, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 590-596)
      See also: Oversize, box 65, folder 1142
    - Wheelock, John Hall, 1951 Dec 12 (Box 30, Folder 597)
    - Whistler, Laurence, 1936-70 (Box 30, Folder 598-599)
    - Whitney, W. Bevan, 1950-73, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 600-609)
    - Wm. C. Elly, Antiquarian Bookseller, 1936-39 (Box 30, Folder 610)
    - Winters, Yvor, 1961 Dec 12 (Box 30, Folder 611)
    - Wright, James, 1951-71 (Box 30, Folder 612)
    - "Y" general, 1931-72 (Box 30, Folder 613)
    - Yale University Library, 1951-76 (Box 30, Folder 614)
      See also: Pearson, Norman Holmes, Box 19 folder 390; Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, Box 28 folder 566
    - Young, Douglas, 1928-62 (Box 30, Folder 615-617)
    - Zoological Society of London, 1931 (Box 30, Folder 618)
    - Greetings on Hodgson's 90th birthday, 1961 (Box 30, Folder 619-622)
      Poems by many of these authors, gathered by Norman Holmes Pearson and presented to Hodgson on his birthday may be found in box 41, folder 878
    - Photocopies of letter from President John F. Kennedy, [1961] (Box 31, Folder 623)
      Original in folder 620
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1887-1971, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 624)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - The Biosophical Review to Siegfried Sassoon, 1934 Jan 18 (Box 31, Folder 625)
    - Dulau and Company, Ltd. to Siegfried Sassoon, 1929 Feb 28 (Box 31, Folder 626)
    - Dwork, Kermit to Siegfried Sassoon, [1951] Aug 16 (Box 31, Folder 627)
    - Martin, Edward A. to "My Dear Sir", 1912 Feb 15 (Box 31, Folder 628)
    - Milner, Alfred B. to Mr. Dean, 1926 Sep 23 (Box 31, Folder 629)
    - Page, Wesley T. to Miss E. Brampton, [19]23 Jul 21 (Box 31, Folder 630)
    - Salt, Henry to [George E. Dartnell?] typescript copy of a letter dated [18]94 Apr 16, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 631)
    - Stead, W. T. to C. Gould, Esq., 1895 Oct 3 (Box 31, Folder 632)
    - Stead, W. T. to Rev. J. Page Hopps, 1893-97 (Box 31, Folder 633)
    - Stead, W. T. to Mrs. Murray, 1896 Feb 18 (Box 31, Folder 634)
    - ?, David to Hester ?, n.y. Nov 12 (Box 31, Folder 635)
  - PERMISSIONS
    - "A-B" general, 1921-69, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 636)
    - Bird, Kenneth, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 637)
    - Birney, Mary G., 1948 (Box 31, Folder 638)
    - Butterley, Nigel, [1956]-57 (Box 31, Folder 639)
    - "C" general, 1920-61 (Box 31, Folder 640)
    - Caldwell, Thomas, 1923 (Box 31, Folder 641)
    - Cecil, David, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 642)